{
    "id": "9ce96bd4ff964d20bccc0cdc608d1e3c",
    "title": "Gap Fills Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "………………………….. the existence of antidrug laws, drug dealers persist in selling drugs illegally.",
            "description": "We need a preposition before a noun. Although is used before a clause.",
            "answers": [
                "Despite",
                "However",
                "Although"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… we have anti-drug laws, drug dealers continue to sell narcotics illegally.",
            "description": "We use although to introduce a clause.",
            "answers": [
                "However",
                "In spite of",
                "Although"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The writer ………………………. that global warming is a major threat to the planet.",
            "description": "We use the simple present to talk about opinions.",
            "answers": [
                "feels",
                "feel",
                "is feeling"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… my childhood was peaceful, my adulthood is very hectic and stressful.",
            "description": "We use while to connect two contrasting ideas.",
            "answers": [
                "As",
                "Since",
                "While"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. I get sunburn quite easily, I don’t sunbathe.",
            "description": "Since can introduce the reason or cause.",
            "answers": [
                "While",
                "Because of",
                "Since"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………….. I studied at university I sold burgers.",
            "description": "We can use while to talk about two situations that happen at the same time.",
            "answers": [
                "Since",
                "Whereas",
                "While"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The schools cancelled the classes after the thunderstorm ………………………….. students could be safe.",
            "description": "We use so that to express intention or purpose.",
            "answers": [
                "so as to",
                "so that",
                "such that"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………………. his long legs, he is a good basketball player.",
            "description": "All of these can be used to indicate the reason.",
            "answers": [
                "Due to",
                "Because of",
                "Owing to",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "Companies don’t want to invest in countries where taxes are high. ………………………… increasing taxes will affect the economy.",
            "description": "Therefore is a transitional adverb. It does not connect two clauses. So is a conjunction. It connects two clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "Because",
                "Therefore",
                "So"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Companies don’t want to invest in countries where taxes are high ………………………… increasing taxes will affect the economy.",
            "description": "So is a coordinating conjunction that connects two clauses of equal rank.",
            "answers": [
                "because",
                "so",
                "therefore"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………. companies don’t want to invest in countries where taxes are high, increasing taxes will affect the economy.",
            "description": "Both since and because can give the reason for something.",
            "answers": [
                "Since",
                "Because",
                "So"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I enjoy reading books ………………………. motivate me.",
            "description": "The relative pronoun that can refer to both people and things. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "that",
                "what"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}